워킹데드 지난 이야기...
Previously on AMC's
"The Walking Dead"
- 물린거요
- 총에 맞았습니다
- Was he bit?
- Shot.
배를 갈라야합니다.
출혈 부위를 찾아서 꿰매야해요
I have to open him up,
find the bleeder and stitch it.
인공호흡기가 필요할겁니다.
제가 데려다 드리죠
You need a respirator.
이런데서 혼자 있는 애를
생각하면...
The thought of her,
out here by herself...
꼬마애를 찾게 되면,
We're gonna locate
that little girl.
그냥 아무 탈 없을거예요
She's gonna be just fine.
2마일 정도 내려가시면 농장이에요
우편함이 보이실껍니다
Two miles down is our farm.
You'll see the mailbox...
혈압이 떨어지고있어
더이상 기다릴 수 없소
Pressure's dropping
We can't wait much longer.
셰인이 돌아온다고 했다면
꼭 돌아올거야
If Shane said he'll be back,
he'll be back.
가이브러쉬이히히~
The Walking Dead S02E03
"Save The Last Dance"
"Save The Last One"
Made by Mikhel for: Subtitulos.es
==SPREAD THE WORD==
가이브러쉬히힝~
Made by Mikhel for: Subtitulos.es
Corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
릭, 그냥..
Rick, just...
약해지면 안돼...
You've got to keep
your strength up.
로리 당신..
Lori, did you...
이건 사람들 입에 오르내리는건데..
I mean, it was legendary.
셰인이 예전에 킹슬리씨의 차를
훔쳤다는 거 들은적 있어?
Did you ever hear about the time
Shane stole Kingsley's car?
응
Yeah.
교장의 차였어
The Principal's car
선생님들의 차량 주차 공간에서
right out of the teacher's lot
그것도 대낮에 말이야
in the middle of a school day.
셰인은 점심시간에 나와서
그 곳으로 곧장 달려갔지
Shane steps out of lunch
and makes a beeline
킹슬리 교장 선생님의 현대 차..
to Kingsley's Hyundai...
시동 선을 연결하고 차를 몰아서
닭 농장이 있는 곳으로 갔지
Wires the ignition, peels out,
drives down Dylan Drive
시동 선을 연결하고 차를 몰아서
닭 농장이 있는 곳으로 갔지
to that chicken farm out there.
전에 이 얘기 들어봤지?
You've heard
this before, right?
셰인은 교장의 차를 가장 큰
우리 안에다 몰아넣어뒀어
So he pulls it into one
of the big holding pens.
매일 차량을 깨끗이
닦았던 킹슬리 교장은
Kingsley, he waxed
that thing every month;
세차장 진공청소기도
매주 사용할 정도였지
had the auto shop
vacuum it out every week.
셰인은 이백여개의 로드 아일랜드 레즈와 같이
그 커다란 우리에 차를 주차시켰어
(※로드 아일랜드 레즈 : 닭의 한 품종)
Shane, he parks it
in this huge pen
with a couple of hundred
Rhode Island reds.
셰인은 차량 뒷 좌석에
씨앗이 들어있는 가방을 열어둔채 두고,
He busts open bags of seed
in the back seat,
차량의 모든 창문을 열어뒀지
rolls down all the windows,
그러고는 학교로 쏜살같이 돌아왔어
and then starts sprinting
back to school.
3마일 정도는 쉽지
It's three miles away easy.
셰인은 점심 시간을 끝마치는
종이 울리기 전에 돌아왔어
He's back in time to finish his
sandwich before the bell.
종이 울렸고,
And then the bell rings.
셰인은 복도에서 킹슬리
교장 선생님과 마주쳤지
Shane gets up and when he runs
into Kingsley in the hallway
그가 창 밖을 바라보며 말하길,
he looks out the window
and says,
"킹슬리 교장선생님,
"Principal Kingsley,
선생님의 쿠페가 없어졌어요."
your coupe's gone."
쿠페말이야,
닭장을 말하는거였어
(※Coupe : 차량, Coop : 닭장)
Coupe, like chicken coop.
알아들었어
I get it.
당연하지
Of course you do.
천 번은 넘게 들은 이야기니까
You've heard this story
1000 times.
당신이 아까 한 말,
맞아
What you said before,
you're right.
셰인은 의사 선생님이 필요하다던
물건을 다 챙겨서 돌아올거야
Shane's gonna make it back
with what the doctor needs.
해낼거야
He'll make it back.
허셀 아저씨가 말하길
당신 뭐 좀 먹어야 한다던데
Hershel said you need to eat.
칼은 괜찮아 질거야
Carl's gonna be all right.
제발 날 위해서라도
Please, for me.
당신은 기운을 차려야해
You've got to keep
your strength up.
탄창이 필요해
I need my clip now.
밖에 나가서 소피아를 찾아보겠어
I'm gonna walk the road,
look for the girl.
저도 같이 가요
I'm coming too.
애 좀 찾아보고 올게요
가는 길에 빛 좀 비춰주쇼
I'm going for a walk.
Shine some light in the forest.
애가 가까이 있다면
불빛을 볼 수 있겠지
If she's out there,
give her something to look at.
- 자네 지금 그게 좋은 생각인것
같나? / - 데일 아저씨
- You think that's a good idea right now?
- Dale.
저 창문,
반대편엔 뭐가 있죠?
Those windows,
what's on the other side?
그냥 아무것도 잡을 것 없이 떨어지는
거요, 덤불이 좀 있으려나
About a 20-foot drop with nothing
to catch you, maybe some bushes,
- 그리고는 운동장이 있을겁니다
- 우린 지금 시간이 필요해요
- then the athletic field.
- We just need enough time.
우린 저걸 잡아야돼요
저걸 잡아서 연 다음 나가야합니다
We got to get up there.
We got to get 'em open and get out.
- 난 안되겠지만 그쪽은 되겠죠
- 이봐요 이봐요
- Not me. Maybe you.
- Hey hey hey.
이봐요, 날 보슈,
정말 내가 저 작은 창문으로
Come on, man, look at me.
You really think I can squeeze through
나갈 수 있을거같아요?
말도 안돼지
one of them tiny windows?
They'd be all over us.
봐요, 일단 녀석들 머리에
총 몇 방을 갈깁시다
Look, we lay down some fire
to get a head start.
당신은 여기 있고
제가 내려가서 놈들을 유인하겠소
You stay here.
I hop down and draw them away.
그럼 저기 객석에 있는 창문에
올라갈 수 있는 기회가 생길거요
That gives you the chance to get
up the bleachers and out a window.
그럼 당신은 어디가요?
And where do you go?
저 아래에 있는
라커룸에 갈게요
Locker room down those steps.
갇히기 딱 좋은 곳인데요?
Looks like a good way
to get trapped.
나 몸집보다 큰
창문이 있을겁니다
It's got windows too,
and more my size.
라커룸에 있는 창문으로 나갈테니
운동장에서 같이 만납시다
I get out through one, I double
back, we meet up out on the field.
당신 제대로 미쳤군요
그쵸?
You're a crazy son
of a bitch, ain't you?
아이한테 도움이 된다면야
Just trying to do right
for that boy.
3방 쏘고 출발하세요
You take three shots
and you go.
그 다음은 제가 쏠게요
뒤를 봐드릴게요
After that I fire.
I'll lay down a cover for you.
- 제가 지시내릴게요
- 알았소
- I'll get you a lead.
- All right.
으악!
Oh God.
초인종 누를까요?
So do we ring the bell?
그니까 제말은.. 여기도
사람이 사는 곳이잖아요
I mean it looks like
people live here.
그런거 할 때는 지났잖아
안그래?
We're past this kind
of stuff, aren't we?
남을 배려하는거 말이야
Having to be considerate.
운전하고 올 때, 도로 게이트를
닫고 왔어요?
Did you close the gate
up the road when you drove in?
어, 안녕하세요
Uh, hi.
네, 닫고 왔어요
Yes, we closed it.
잠그고, 암튼 뭐 다했어요
Did the latch and everything.
다시 만나서 반가워요
Hello.
Nice to see you again.
아까 잠깐 만났었죠
We met before briefly.
도와드리러 왔어요
저희가 할 수 있는 일이 없을까요?
Look, we came to help.
There anything we can do?
물린거 아니에요
저 혼자 나대다가 심하게 다친거에요
It's not a bite.
I cut myself pretty bad though.
저희가 봐드릴게요
당신들이 왔다고 전하고 오죠
We'll have it looked at.
I'll tell them you're here.
저희 진통제랑
항생제 갖고 있어요
We have some painkillers
and antibiotics.
이 사람한텐 벌써 줬구요
칼이 필요하다면..
I already gave him some.
If Carl needs any.
일단 안으로 들어가요
먹을거 차려드릴게요
Come on inside.
I'll make you something to eat.
안녕하세요
Hey.
왔어?
저희도 여기 있을게요
Um, we're here, okay?
고마워
Thank you.
뭐든 필요하면..
Whatever you need.
그들이 곧 돌아오지 않으면
결정을 내려야해요
They don't get back soon, we're
gonna have a decision to make.
어떤..?
And that is?
인공호흡기 없이
있을 수 있는지 봐야합니다
Whether to operate on your
boy without the respirator.
- 그건 힘들다면서요?
- 그래요
- You said that wouldn't work.
- I know.
가능성이 매우 낮지만,
더이상 기다릴 수 없어요
It's extremely unlikely.
But we can't wait much longer.
우리가 소피아를 찾을 수 있다고
생각해요?
You really think
we're gonna find Sophia?
당신도 다른 사람들과 같은
표정이나 짓고 있군
You got that look on your face
당신도 다른 사람들과 같은
표정이나 짓고 있군
same as everybody else.
다들 왜 그래?
What the hell's wrong
with you people?
- 이제 막 찾기 시작했잖아
- 그래요?
- We just started looking.
- Well, do you?
티벳에 있는 산에서 찾는 것도 아니고,
여긴 조지아야
It ain't the mountains of Tibet.
It's Georgia.
농장이나 뭐 그런데서
잘 버티고 있을거야
She could be holed up
in a farmhouse somewhere.
길을 잃고, 다시 살고 뭐 그런거지
People get lost
and they survive.
- 늘 있는 일이야
- 소피아는 12살 밖에 안됐어요
- It happens all the time.
- She's only 12.
내가 길을 잃었을 땐
소피아보다 어릴 때 였어
Hell, I was younger
than her and I got lost.
숲에서 산딸기 먹으면서
9일을 버텼어
Nine days in the woods
eating berries,
옻나무 잎으로 똥도 닦고
wiping my ass with poison oak.
다른 사람들이 찾았어요?
They found you?
우리집 꼰대는 종업원이랑
술먹고 노닥거리고 있었고
My old man was off on
a bender with some waitress.
형은 소년원에서 형량 채우고 있었지
Merle was doing another
stint in juvie.
내가 사라진지도 몰랐어
Didn't even know I was gone.
내가 알아서 혼자 돌아왔지
I made my way back though.
곧장 부엌으로 달려가서
샌드위치를 만들어 먹었어
Went straight into the kitchen
and made myself a sandwich.
옷은 말할 것도 없고
No worse for wear.
똥꼬가 좀 심하게
가려웠지만 뭐..
Except my ass itched
something awful.
미안해요
I'm sorry.
정말 끔찍한 이야기네요
I'm sorry, that is
a terrible story.
소피아의 경우에 다른 점은
사람들이 찾고 있다는 거야
Only difference is Sophia's
got people looking for her.
이번 실종의 장점이라 할 수 있지
I call that an advantage.
아마 이 세상은 이제 더이상
아이들을 위한 곳은 아닌거같아
Maybe this isn't a world
for children anymore.
맞아 근데 뭐,
우리는 애가 있어
Yeah well, we have a child.
칼은 지금 이 세상에 함께 있잖아
Carl is here in this world now.
그래선 안되는걸지도 모르지
Maybe he shouldn't be.
아마도 이래야하는 걸지도 몰라
Maybe this is how
it's supposed to be.
진심은 아니겠지?
You can't mean that.
그래 알았어
Okay.
All right.
당신의 뜻은 이해할 수 있어
I can understand that
thought crossing your mind.
내가 생각하려고 해서 생각나는게 아니야
그런 생각이 멈추지 않는단 말이야
It didn't cross my mind, Rick.
I can't stop thinking it.
왜 우리가 이런 세상에서
칼과 함께 살 생각을 하는거지?
Why do we want Carl
to live in this world?
이런 삶을?
To have this life?
그럼 칼은 사람들이 찢겨져 죽는걸
더 많이 볼 수 있겠네?
So he can see more people
torn apart in front of him?
또 배고프고 겁에 질려있고..
So that he can be
hungry and scared
지금까지처럼..
for however long
he has before he...
계속 도망가고, 도망가고, 또 도망가서
So he can run and run
and run and run
결국 살아 남는다 쳐도,
and then even if he
survives he ends up...
결국은 생존밖에 모르는 짐승이 될 뿐이잖아
he ends up just another animal who
doesn't know anything except survival?
칼이 만약..
If he...
칼이 만약 오늘 죽는다면..
if he dies tonight,
칼에게 있어선 좋은거야
it ends for him.
왜 다른 방법이 더 좋아는거야?
Tell me why it would
be better another way.
뭐가 바뀐거야?
What changed?
뭐?
What?
제너 박사가 우리에게
출구를 알려줬을 때
Jenner offered us a way out.
당신은 그에게 계속 우리가
살아갈 수 있도록 하게 해 달라고 그랬어
You asked him
to let us keep trying.
빌기까지 했어
You begged him.
"할 수 있을 때까지"라고 말했지
뭐가 바뀐거야?
"For as long as we can," you said.
What changed?
그건 지난 일이잖아
There was a moment
the other day...
잠시 동안이었지만
재키가 죽은걸 잊고 있었어
It was just a second
but I forgot Jacqui was dead.
돌아서서
그녀에게 하고 싶은 말이 있었어
I turned around, I wanted
to tell her something.
거의 그녀의 이름을 부를 뻔 했어
근데 그건 잠시였고 곧 기억났지
I almost said her name.
It was just a second and then I remembered.
그치만 생각해보면
그녀는 이제 이런걸 볼 일이 없는거야
But then I realized she
didn't have to see any of it.
고속도로, 워커들..
소피아, 총에 맞은 칼..
The highway, the herds,
Sophia, Carl getting shot...
그녀는 이제..
she didn't...
그녀는 이제 더이상
이런걸 두려워할 필요가 없는거야
She doesn't have
to be afraid anymore.
배고프고 화나고
Hungry.
Angry.
이건 멈추지 않을거야 릭
It hasn't stopped
happening, Rick.
이건 마치 우리가 목에 칼을 대고
매일을 살아가는 것과 같아
It's like we live with a knife at our
throats every second of every day.
하지만 재키는 아니야.
더이상 그렇지 않지.
But Jacqui doesn't.
Not anymore.
그리고는..
And then...
제너 박사 말이 맞았다고 생각해
I thought,
"Maybe Jenner was right."
그건 받아들이지 않을래
I don't accept that.
그건 말도 안돼는거야
I can't accept that.
그는 굴복한거야
그가 말한건..
That man surrendered.
It doesn't matt...
그가 뭐라했든 상관없어
it doesn't matter what he said.
전혀
None of it.
당신은 정말 이게 옳다고 생각해?
칼이 죽는게..
You really think it would
be better if Carl...
우리가 포기하는 것이?
if we just gave up?
칼이 살게 되면 뭐가 더 좋은지
얘기해봐
Tell me why it would
be better the other way.
제발
Please.
형씨 죽은 줄 알았잖아요
Man, I thought I'd lost you.
방금 그게 마지막 총알이었어요
That was my last rifle round.
- 제꺼도요
- 얼른 갑시다
- Mine too.
- Come on.
얼른 서둘러요!
Come on.
- 여기 어디에요?
- 헤이~ 우리 아들!
- Where are we?
- Hey, little man.
이 분은 허셸 씨야
That's Hershel.
이 아저씨 집에 있어
We're in his house.
넌 사고를 당했단다
You had an accident.
- 괜찮아?
- 너무.. 아파요
- All right?
- It hurts, a lot.
그래 아가, 알아
Oh baby, I know.
I know.
- 그거 보셨어요?
- 뭘?
- You should have seen it.
- What?
사슴이요
The deer.
너무 예뻤어요 엄마
It was so pretty, mom.
진짜 가까웠어요
It was so close.
전 지금까지 그렇게..
I've never been...
칼?
Carl?
무슨 일이죠?
What is happening?
그러지 마세요
발작입니다
Don't. It's a seizure.
차분하게 하려다가
칼을 다치게 할 수도 있어요
If you hold him down,
you could hurt him.
- 멈추게 하실 순 없어요?
- 어차피 겪어야 할 일입니다.
- You can't stop it?
- He has to just go through it.
칼의 뇌가 충분한 양의
피를 공급받지 못하고 있어요
His brain isn't
getting enough blood.
혈압이 떨어지고 있어요
수혈이 더 필요하겠습니다
His pressure is bottoming.
He needs another transfusion.
- 알겠어요. 준비됐습니다.
- 당신의 피를 더 빼버린다면,
- Okay, I'm ready.
- If I take any more out of you
몸이 다칠 수가 있어요
혼수상태에 빠진단 말이오
your body could shut down.
You could go into a coma.
- 심장 마비가 올 수도 있어요
- 시간이 없어요
- Or cardiac arrest.
- You're wasting time.
어서요
이 곳을 빠져나가야해요
Come on, man.
We need a way out.
- 잠시 숨 좀 고릅시다
- 어서요
- Just let me catch my breath.
- Come on.
잠이 안와?
Can't sleep?
그들이 돌아오기 전까지 기다리려구요
I'm gonna wait for them
to come back.
아래로 내려가셔서
눈 좀 붙이세요
You can go down and sleep
if you want to.
아냐, 같이 둘러보지 뭐
No, we can keep watch together.
어느 쪽으로 갔어요?
Which way did they go?
젠장 뭐야?
What the hell?
"난 물렸다. 열도 나고,"
"Got bit.
Fever hit.
"세상이 욧돼버렸어. 이젠 끝낼 때인가"
World gone to shit.
Might as well quit."
병신, 지 머리를 쏴서
자살해야하는 것도 몰랐군
Dumbass didn't know enough
to shoot himself in the head.
자기 스스로를 정육점 돼지처럼
만들어버렸잖아
Turned himself into a big
swinging piece of bait.
개판이구만
And a mess.
괜찮아?
You all right?
토하지 않으려는 중이에요
Trying not to puke.
- 토하고 싶음 해
- 아녜요 괜찮아요
- Go ahead if you gotta.
- No, I'm fine.
우리 잠시 다른 얘기나 하죠
Let's just talk about
something else for a minute.
- 그런거 쏘는건 어떻게 배웠어요?
- 먹어야 했거든
- How'd you learn to shoot?
- Gotta eat.
이 녀석들과 우리가 가진
유일한 공통점인 것..
That's one thing these walkers
and us have in common.
지금보니 이녀석 이렇게 가까이 우리같은
먹이가 보이는건 처음인거같은데
I guess it's the closest he's
been to food since he turned.
엄청 큰 피냐타(Pinata)처럼 매달려있군 그래
Hanging up there
like a big pinata.
딴 놈들이 와서 이 녀석의 신선한
다리를 다 먹은것 같군
The other geeks came and ate
all the flesh off his legs.
우리 딴 얘기 하기로 했잖아요
I thought we were
changing the subject.
내 똥꼬 간지러운 얘기 듣고
웃은거에 대한 복수라 치자고
Call that payback for
laughing about my itchy ass.
많이 올라오진 않았네요
There wasn't a lot
that came up.
하..
Huh.
돌아가자구
Let's head back.
당신 저거 ..?
Aren't you gonna...
아니, 피해주는건 없는데 뭐
No.
He ain't hurting nobody.
화살을 더 낭비할 순 없지
Ain't gonna waste
an arrow either.
스스로 결정한건데 뭐
신경쓰지 말자구
He made his choice.
Opted out.
냅둬
Let him hang.
당신 지금 살고 싶어? 아니면 반대야?
You want to live now or not?
그냥 물어보는거야
It's just a question.
대답하면 쏴죽이세요
An answer for an arrow.
어때요?
Fair?
제가 살고싶은지 나도 모르겠어요
I don't know if I want to live
그래야하든..
or if I have to
그냥 버릇인지..
or if it's just a habit.
대답같지도 않군
Not much of an answer.
화살 하나 날렸네
Waste of an arrow.
걱정하실거 없어요
데릴이랑 같이 있으니
You don't need to worry.
She's with Daryl.
무슨 일이 생기더라도
그가 보호해 줄거예요
If something happens
he can protect her.
제 말 들으셨죠?
You hear what I'm saying?
미안, 내가 들은건
무슨 일이 생긴다는 거였어
Sorry, all I heard was
if something happens.
잠시 좀 보고 있겠어?
You mind keeping watch?
어떻게 하는지 몰라요
I don't know how to use that.
장시간 자릴 비우진
않을거야
I won't be gone long.
뭔가가 보이면
날 불러
If you see anything, call out.
멀리 가지 않을테니
들을 수 있어
I'm not going far.
I'll hear you.
제때 왔군요
You got here right in time.
치료 안했다면 오래 가지 못했을거야
This couldn't go
untreated much longer.
"멀 딕슨"
"Merle Dixon."
항생제 들고 온 친구 이름인가?
Is that your friend
with the antibiotics?
아뇨 아줌마 멀은 더이상
우리와 함께 있지 않아요
No, ma'am.
Merle's no longer with us.
데릴이 준... 그의 동생이에요
Daryl gave us those...
his brother.
그를 친구라 불러도 될까 모르겠네
Not sure I'd call him a friend.
친구 맞네. 이 독시사이클린이
당신 생명을 구했으니까
He is today. This doxycycline
might have just saved your life.
멀이 뭐 땜에 이 약을 챙겼는지 알아요?
You know what Merle
was taking it for?
임질이요
The clap.
음.. 성병이죠
Um, venereal disease.
데릴이 말해준거예요
That's what Daryl said.
멀 딕슨이란 사람이 성병이 걸린건
당신한테 생긴 최고의 일이네요
I'd say Merle Dixon's clap was the
best thing to ever happen to you.
그런 생각은 최대한
안하려 노력중이에요
I'm really trying
not to think about that.
기도해요?
Are you praying?
왜 자꾸 사람들한테 몰래 접근해요?
Why do you sneak up
on people so much?
당신은 뭔가 몰래 다가가기 편해요
You're easy to sneak up on.
기도하고 있었어요
I was praying.
잘 안되네요
I was trying to.
종교 있어요?
기도 자주 하세요?
You religious?
You pray a lot?
사실 이게 처음 하는건데
Actually this was my first try.
한 번도?
Ever?
와우. 미안해요
Wow. Sorry.
당신의 첫 기도를 망칠 생각은 없었는데
I didn't mean to wreck
your first time.
신께서도 기도의 요점은
아셨을거예요
God probably got the gist.
- 왜 기도하죠?
- 친구들때문에요
- Praying for what?
- My friends.
모두들 조금씩이나마 도움이
필요할 듯 보여서요
Looks like they could all
use a little help right now.
당신은..
You think...
당신은 신이 존재한다고 생각하세요?
you think God exists?
늘 믿어왔죠
I always took it on faith.
요 근래에는 좀 궁금하네요
Lately I've wondered.
이 모든 일이 생기면서..
Everything that's happened,
사람들이 엄청나게
많은 기도를 했을거예요
there must have been a lot
of praying going on.
꽤 많은 기도가 답을 못받았겠지만..
It seems quite a few
went unanswered.
고맙네요
꽤 도움이 되는군요
Thanks.
This is really helping.
미안해요
계속 하세요
Sorry.
Go ahead.
진짜에요
Really.
보실거예요?
You gonna watch?
전 커피 리필해드리죠
I'll get you a refill instead.
제 일이 아닌건 알지만
I know it's not my business,
신이 있다고 믿으면
자유로워져요
and feel free
to believe in God,
중요한건 어떻게든 괜찮을 수
있도록 하는거예요
but the thing is you've got
to make it okay somehow
어떤 일이 생기든간에..
no matter what happens.
칼이 총에 맞기 전에
Before it happened
우린 숲에 서있었어
we were standing there
in the woods
근데 사슴 한마리가
and this deer
우리들 앞에 나타났지
just crossed
right in front of us.
맹세컨데 사슴이 그냥 거기 있었던거야
I swear it just
planted itself there
난 칼을 주시하고 있었어
and looked Carl
right in the eye.
칼을 봤더니
And I looked at Carl
칼은 사슴을 보고있고
사슴 또한 칼을 보고 있었지
looking at that deer, and that
deer looking right back at Carl.
그리고 그 순간은..
And that moment just...
순식간에 지나갔어
slipped away.
순식간에
It slipped away.
이게 칼이 깼을 때 했던 얘기야
That's what he was talking
about when he woke up,
총에 맞은거나
not about getting shot
교회에서 있었던 일을
얘기하려는게 아니었어
or what happened at the church.
칼은 아름다운 거에 대해
얘기했던거야
He talked about
something beautiful,
살아있는 무언가 말이야
something living.
아직 우리를 위한 삶은 있어
There's still a life for us,
이 곳과 같은 장소에서
a place maybe like this.
저 밖에 죽음만이 있는건 아니야
It isn't all death out there.
그럴리 없어
It can't be.
우리가 무엇을 보든지 간에
우린 단지 스스로 강해져야할 뿐이야
We just have to be
strong enough
우리가 무엇을 보든지 간에
우린 단지 스스로 강해져야할 뿐이야
after everything we've seen
to still believe that.
칼이 왜 이런 세상에서 사는걸
좋지 않다고 생각해?
Why is it better for Carl
to live even in this world?
칼은 사슴 얘기를 했어 로리
He talked about the deer, Lori.
칼은 사슴 얘기를 했다고
He talked about the deer.
오 젠장
Oh, shit.
길에 닿아야해요
트럭에 돌아가야만 합니다
Got to get to the street,
double back to the truck.
- 이봐요, 우린 해낼 수 없을겁니다.
알았어요?/- 시도는 해봅시다
- Look, we ain't gonna make it, okay?
- Got to try, man.
- 어서요. 일어나요
- 이 가방을 챙기세요
- Come on, get up.
- You're gonna take these bags
- 얼른 가세요
- 당신을 두고 혼자 갈 순 없소
- and you're gonna go.
- I ain't leaving you behind.
알았어요
Okay.
총알 얼마나 남았어요?
How many rounds you got left?
4발요, 당신은?
Four. You?
다섯 발요. 하나는 파이프에 있고
Five and one in the pipe.
우리가 피를 채워주는 것 보다
빠르게 피가 부족해지고 있어요
He's still losing blood
faster than we can replace it.
그리고 복부가 팽창하고 있어요
And with the swelling
in his abdomen
더이상 기다릴 수 없습니다.
we can't wait any longer
그렇지 않으면 죽을겁니다.
or he's just going
to slip away.
이제 확실하게
말해주셔야겠네요
Now I need to know right now
제가 이걸 하게 하실건지
if you want me to do this,
왜냐면 이젠 정말 시간이
없으니까요
because I think your boy
is out of time.
선택하셔야합니다.
You have to make a choice.
- 선택이요?
- 선택하자
- A choice?
- A choice.
어떻게 할지 말해줘
You have to tell me what it is.
시작하자
We do it.
좋아요. 침대 모서리 부분을 잡으세요
Okay, get the corner
of that bed.
시트를 내립시다
Let's get the sheets down.
거기 시트 위에
I.V 가방을 챙겨요
Get the I.V. bag
on the sheet.
좋아요 셋에 들어올립니다.
Okay, on three.
하나, 둘, 셋!
One, two, three.
릭, 로리
Rick, Lori,
물러서는게 좋을거예요
you may want to step out.
세상에
Oh God.
칼과 함께 있어줘
You stay here with him.
- 칼은?
- 아직 기회는 있어
- Carl?
- There's still a chance.
오티스는??
Otis?
돌아오지 못했어요
No.
패트리샤에겐 아무말도 마시오
We say nothing to Patricia.
수술 후까지는.
그녀가 필요합니다.
Not till after.
I need her.
코너를 돌 때마다 계속해서
우릴 막아섰어
They kept blocking us
at every turn.
아무것도 남지 않았었어
총알도 10발도 채 남지 않았었고
We had nothing left.
We were down to 10 rounds.
그리고선 그가..
그리고선 그가 나를 엄호해준댔어
Then he said...
he said he'd cover me
난 계속해서 가야만 했지
and that I should keep going.
계속 가고 있었어,
계속..
So that's what I did.
I just...
계속 가고있는데...
I kept going.
But I...
뒤를 돌아보니 그가..
I looked back and he...
난 노력했어
I tried.
오티스는 꼬마의 수술이
진행되기를 바랬어
He wanted to make it right.
안드레아 기다려
Andrea.
Wait.
뭘 원해요 데일 아저씨?
What do you want, Dale?
이걸 주려고
To give you this.
널 걱정했단다
I care about you
그래서 널 위해 결정했지..
so I made a choice
for you... choices.
내가 왜 이러는지는 아는데
이건 내 총이 아니야
I know why I did it,
but this is not my gun.
널 위해 결정한 이 선택도
내가 내린건 아니지만..
And the choices
that I made for you
널 위해 결정한 이 선택도
내가 내린건 아니지만..
were not mine to make.
그치만 아직 부탁할 순 있어
But I can still ask,
너를 죄책감에 들게 하려는건 아니지만
부탁할 순 있잖아
and this is not
to make you guilty
너를 죄책감에 들게 하려는건 아니지만
부탁할 순 있잖아
or put me ahead of you,
but I can still ask,
제발..
please...
날 후회하게 만들진 말아다오
Don't make me regret this.
제가 망 볼게요
I'll take watch.
그럼 지금 나를 용서..
So do you forgive me for...
날 용서해주는거니?
do you forgive me?
노력 중이에요
I'm trying.
어릴 때부터 오티스 아저씨를
알고 지냈어요
I've known Otis
since I was a kid.
저의 엄마가 돌아가신 후에
이 농장으로 오셨죠
He's run this farm
since before my mother died.
또 누가..?
Who else?
또 누구를 잃었어요?
Who'd you lose?
어떻게든 괜찮아지게
만들라면서요
You told me I had
to make it okay somehow.
그게 당신이 늘 하던거잖아요
안그래요?
That's what you've been
trying to do, right?
누구죠?
Which ones?
새엄마예요
Stepmother.
배다른 오빠고
Stepbrother.
안정을 취한 것 같습니다.
He seems to have stabilized.
세상에
Oh God.
드릴 말씀이 없네요
I don't have words.
저도 그렇네요
어떤 말이든 드려야하는데
I don't either.
Wish I did.
페트리샤한테 오티스 일을
어떻게 말할까싶습니다.
How do I tell Patricia
about Otis?
칼한테 가봐
You go to Carl.
난 허셸씨와 같이 갈게
I'll go with Hershel.
여기 있어
Stay.
화장실은 윗층에 있어요
The bathroom's upstairs.
- 옷 몇 개 가져 왔어요
- 고맙습니다.
- I brought you some clothes.
- Thank you.
옷이 맞진 않을거예요
오티스 아저씨꺼라..
They won't fit well.
They were Otis's.
총알 얼마 남았어요?
How many
rounds you got left?
4발이요. 당신은?
Four. You?
다섯 발하고 하나는 파이프에 있어요
Five and one in the pipe.
어서 서둘러요
Come on.
- 한 발 남았어요
- 저도
- Down to my last.
- Me too.
미안해요..
I'm sorry.
얼른 내놔요!!
Will you give it...
Ah!
내놔!!
Give it!
죽여버리겠어!
I'll kill you.
이거 놔! 이거 놓으라고!!
Let go of me!
Let go!
Made by Mikhel for: Subtitulos.es
Corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
Subtitulos.es
==SPREAD THE WORD==